Price, Wolfgang S. Papers 5041
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Wolfgang S. Price Papers
1955-1960
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Price, Wolfgang S.
5041
0.5 cubic feet
0.5 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
Consists of research materials used by Price for his MS thesis, submitted to the NYSSILR at Cornell University, entitled "Prevailing Wage Rate Determination for Municipal Laborers in New York City: Case Study of the Administratiion of Section 220 of the Labor Law."
3337337
Biographical / Historical
At the time he gathered these materials, Wolfgang Price was a graduate student at the New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations in 1960.
Woflgang Price received a BS from Marquette University (1959) and an MS from the New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations at Cornell (1960). Prior to his formal education, Mr. Price served in the U.S. Air Force, was a hospital administrator in Milwaukee, Wis., and an intern for the National Mediation Board. As of 1982, he was a consultant, with offices in Silver Spring, Md.
Scope and Contents
Consists of research materials used by Price for his MS thesis, submitted to the New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations at Cornell University, entitled "Prevailing Wage Rate Determination for Municipal Laborers in New York City: Case Study of the Administration of Section 220 of the Labor Law."
Includes copies of determinations on wage rates pursuant to section 220 of the Labor Law of New York State for selected classes of laborers employed by the City of New York; claims of laborers employed by the City of New York for the fixation of wages pursuant to section 220 (1958-1959); decisions and certificates of extent of representation and of exclusive bargaining unit for the Correction Officers' Benevolent Association (1958); the Uniformed Sanitationmen's Association; Local 831, International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs Warehousemen and Helpers of America (1958); Local 241, N.Y.C. Laborers; and District Council 37, American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (1959).
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives 227 Ives Hall Tower Road Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheelref@cornell.edu https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel/
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, February 20, 2014
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, October 28, 2016
Labor laws and legislation -- New York (State); Municipal officials and employees; Collective bargaining -- Municipal employees -- New York (State) -- New York; Wages -- Municipal employees -- New York (State) -- New York; Price, Wolfgang S., 1930-; AFSCME. District Council 37 (New York, N.Y.); Correction Officers Benevolent Association (New York, N.Y.); New York City Laborers. Local 241; New York (N.Y.). Department of Sanitation; New York (N.Y.). Department of Traffic; New York (State). Department of Correctional Services; Uniformed Sanitationmen's Association
3337337
- Wage Determinations, Maintenance Men, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Determinations, Laborer Classification, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Wage Survey, Laborers, 1955-1957 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Union Wage Demands, Maintenance Workers (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Bureau of Budget, Laborer Classifications, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Scope and Contents
  July 1 1954 - June 30 1955
- Leave Regulations for Employees under Career and Salary Plan, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Minutes, Labor Law Complaint, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  October 7, December 18, January 16 1958
- Minutes, Labor Law Complaint, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  May 13 and 20 1958
- Minutes, Labor Law Complaints, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  February 25, April 14, 16, 20, 24-25,28 1958
- Minutes, Labor Law Complaints., 1959 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  May 23, June 2, 6, December 5 1958, May 15 1959
- Determinations, Black Smiths, Riggers, etc. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- NYC Extent of Representation of Exclusive Bargaining Status, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Wage Survey, Maintenance Men, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 13)